Luiz Eduardo Amaral

Campinas - SP

Q (41) 98808 1625 • ☐ luizamaral306@gmail.com

https://luxedo.github.io/ • in luiz-nishino-amaral • • luxedo

Profile

Passionate senior developer that loves to transform data into inovative solutions

A 10-year career in programming, mainly dedicated to development and maintenance of sensors based on computer vision, as well as hardware prototyping, programming in embedded systems, systems programming, development of detection algorithms with traditional computer vision and deep learning, development of predictive models, and also web development.

In my free time I like to contribute to Open Source projects, having published packages in Python, Ruby and Node. Additionally, I have commits accepted in project documentation on Google, MDN, and scikit-learn, and in code from several other repositories.

Job Experience

TarvosSenior Data Scientist

Campinas
2019–Current

Prototyping and maintenance of a pest detection smart trap

Building datasets of three different classes of agricultural pests;

- Training of image object detection models for pest counting with performance above 95%;
- O Development of Linux systems to execute detection models;
- Development for embedded systems in C, C++ and Rust;
- Creation of classic image-based models for trap operation;
- Planning, management and execution of refactoring of the company's web platform;
- Statistical modeling: Trap capture rate; Ideal distance between the traps; Forecast of pest infestation;
- O Creation of reporting models and publication in microservices architecture.

Dom RockCampinasData Scientist2016–2018

Data Scientist
Analysis and exploration of structured and unstructured data

- Creation and maintenance of ETL pipelines;
- Image analysis, processing and OCR;
- Creation of an image positioning algorithm based on morphological characteristics;
- Experience with statistical models (polynomial regressions, ensemble methods, Bayesian statistics, SVMs, neural networks);
- Implementation of git for version control of the company's code;
- Maintenance of the company's Web system, as well as creation of new screens and views.

Instituto de Biologia Molecular do Paraná

Curitiba

Researcher/Systems Developer

2013-2016

Research in colloids, emulsions, electrospray for synthesis of magnetic beads and strings Prototyping of a lateral flow reader device

- Patent for magnetic microspheres;
- Creation of the diagnostics device hardware and software:
 - Hardware prototyping;
 - Creation of the camera calibration algorithm;
 - Creation of the chip detection and positioning algorithm;
 - Creation of the diagnostics classification algorithm;
 - Development of the graphical interface in PyQt;
 - Publication of libraries to control the MCP3008 and ADS1115 ICs in Python;
 - Registration of software for the device and a patent for the system;

Universidade Federal do Paraná

Curitiba

Undergraduate Researcher/Masters Surfaces and materials research

2008-2013

- O Research into modification of polymers by nitrogen plasma for device sealing lab-on-a-chip;
- Electrowetting research to control the flow of lab-on-a-chip devices;
- Patent for a check valve sealed with ferrofluid that was the subject of the master's thesis;
- Development of a library to control stepper motors with the IC ULN2803A;

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, C/C++, Rust, Elixir, Bash, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, R, Octave, Assembly, PTEX

Systems: Raspberry Pi, ESP32 (ESP-IDF), STM32 (Cube MX, CMake), Raspberry Pi Pico, Arduino, SAM D21

Libraries: TensorFlow, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Scikit-Learn, Jupyter, DVC, OpenCV, NLTK, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Unittest, Black, Ruff, Pre-commit, Scrapy, Requests, Flask, Selenium, Puppeteer, Express, Jest, Mocha, Chai, Eslint, Dotenv, Axios, Handlebars, Twilio, Zod

Google Cloud: Compute Engine, Kubernetes, Firebase, Cloud Functions, Storage, DNS

Databases: MongoDB, SQL, Firestore, Elasticsearch

Others: GNU/Unix, Git, Docker, GDB, CI/CD, TDD, Agile/Scrum/XP

Education

UnicampCampinasPostgraduate2021–2021

Complex Data Mining

UFPR Curitiba 2011-2013

Masters Master of Engineering and Materials Sciences

UFPR Curitiba 2005-2010

Bachelor in Physics

Courses

Graduate

Coursera: Deep Learning Specialization Coursera: Machine Learning Specialization

Coursera: Machine Learning Coursera: Agile Project Management

Coursera: Convolutional Neural Networks Coursera: Agile with Atlassian Jira

Coursera: Cryptography I Coursera: Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Edx: Using Python for Research Coursera: Algorithms, Part I

Edx: I Heart Stats: Learning to Love Statistics Coursera: Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Coursera: Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparame- Edx: DSE210x Probability and Statistics in Data Science

ter tuning, Regularization and Optimization using Python

Languages

Native: Portuguese

Proficient: English

Intermediate: Spanish

Portfolio and Open Source projects

Check my projects at http://luxedo.github.io/

:wq